I would like to talk to you about why many E-off projects fail and I really think that
the most important thing of it is that we stop listening to patients and one of the
things we did at Robert University is we appointed a Chief Listening Officer, not on
a very scientific way, she puts up a little cup of coffee or a cup of tea and asks patients,
family, relatives, what's up? How could we help you? And we think, we like to think that
this is one of the major problems why all, maybe not all, but most of the E-off projects
fail since we stopped listening. This is my weighing skill. It's a very simple thing,
it's got one nut, on, off, and every morning I hop on it and yes, I got a challenge, as
you might see, and I put my challenge on 95 kilograms, but the thing is that it's made
this simple, that whenever I hop on, it sends my data to Google Health as well and it's
collected by my general petitioner as well, so he can see what's my problem in weight,
not on the very moment that I need cardiologic support or something like it, but also looking
back for it. But there's another thing, as some of you might know, I got more than 4,000
followers on Twitter, so every morning I hop on my weighing skill and before I'm in my
car people start talking to me, I think you need a light lunch today, Leshan. But that's
the nicest thing that could happen since this is peer pressure. Peer pressure used to help
patients, since this could be used for B-Stas, it could be used to stop smoking for patients,
but on the other hand it also could be used to get people from out of their chairs and
try to work together in some kind of gaming activity to get more control of their health.
And as of next week, it will be soon available, there will be this little blood pressure meter
connected to an iPhone or something or other, and people will be able from their homes to
take their blood pressure, send it in to their doctor and eventually share it to others,
for instance, for over a hundred dollars. And this is the point where patients get into
position and can collect not only their own control again, being captain of the ownership,
but also can help us in healthcare due to the challenges that we're facing, like healthcare,
cost explosion, double demand and things like that. Make techniques that's easy to use and
start with this to embrace patients in the team. And you could do this with techniques
like this, but also by crowdsourcing. And one of the things we did, I would like to
share with you, introduced by a little video.
We all got navigation controls in our car.
We maybe even got it in our cell phone. We perfectly know where all the ADMs are, just
about the city of Maastricht. The other thing is we know where all the gas stations are.
And sure, we could find fast food chains. But where would be the nearest AED to help
this patient? We asked around and nobody knew. Nobody knew where the nearest life-saving
AED was to obtain, right now. So what we did, we crowdsourced to the Netherlands and we
set up a website and asked the crowd, if you see an AED, please submit it. Tell us
where it is. Tell us when it's open, since sometimes in office hours it's closed of course.
And over 10,000 AEDs in the Netherlands already have been submitted.
The next step we took was find applications for it. And we built an iPad application.
We made an application for layer, augmented reality, to find these AEDs. And whenever
you were in a city like Maastricht and somebody collapsed, you can use your iPhone. And within
the next weeks, also on your Microsoft cell phone. To find the nearest AED, which can
save lives. And as of today, we would like to introduce this not only as AED for you,
which is the product called, but also AED for us. And we would like to start this on
a worldwide level. And asking all colleagues of us in the rest of the world, college universities
to help us to find and work and act like a hub, to crowdsource all these AEDs around
the world. That whenever you are on a holiday and somebody collapses, might it be your own
relative or someone just in front of you, you can find this. The other thing we would
like to ask is companies also all over the world that will be able to help us validate
these AEDs. This might be courier services or cable guys, for instance, just to see whether
the AED that's submitted still is in place. So please help us on this one and try to make
not only health a little bit better, but take control of it. Thank you.